Brian Flanagan

Senior Web Developer

Exton, PA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Brian-Flanagan/1f8802a22bb4b7e5

Experienced Front End/UI Engineer with 14 years experience in standard's-based web application development. Highly motivated, detail-oriented problem solver with a passion for new technologies and proof-of-concept development. Mentored co-workers on best practices and multiple disciplines in web application development. Analytical thinker with excellent planning and research skills. Exceptional ability to provide software and process solutions in collaborative and individual environments. Strong communication skills with the ability to liaison between technical and non-technical individuals.

Proficiencies

JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX, JSON, CSS3, HTML5, Backbone, RequireJS, Mustache, Node.js, REST, Responsive Design, LESS, Bootstrap, Mobile, Photoshop, PHP, SQL, MongoDB, Apache, Agile, Scrum, Jira, SVN, Git

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Web Developer

Trellist, Inc - Wilmington, DE - August 2013 to Present

Responsibilities

Consulted and advised on best practices for implementing Node.js, Responsive Design, NoSQL, and MVC. Developed sites and shells integrating a variety of responsive frameworks including Bootstrap, Foundation and Skeleton as well as custom solutions.

Developed WordPress sites and plugins. Implemented multi-site broadcast support.

Senior Web Developer

Scala, Inc - March 2012 to May 2013

Developed prototype Digital Media CMS integrating Backbone, RequireJS, and MustacheJS into a REST-based single-page web application.

Lead front-end development with an international co-located team.

Senior Web Developer

Pointroll, Inc - September 2011 to March 2012

Developed reporting analysis web application using JavaScriptMVC framework.

Worked as part of a team to develop interactive dynamic ad distribution tool for display of web ads based on known user data.

Senior Interaction Designer

Yellowbook, Inc - October 2009 to September 2011

Developed architecture to support multi-variant and A/B testing for production site changes.

Developed clone of current production site on public-facing server with folder login security, error reporting, Google Analytics and A/B testing integration, search data tracking, and automated updating to match production changes in "LAMP" environment.

Led development of testing site with easily altered components and quick-cloning to support rapid construction of prototypes and test variants.

Developed API's for tag cloud and XML data feeds.

Led development of nine separate multi-variant UI tests.

Led development of more than 50 prototypes and proof-of-concept projects.

Developed custom plugins for the jQuery framework.

Developed projects that consumed data from various API sources in AJAX and Server-Side application development.

Led development of HTML5, CSS3 and mobile platform prototypes.

Developed IAB banners in various formats including XHTML, HTML5 and Flash.

Integrated WordPress solution for corporate site to remove reliance upon Development Team sprints for content changes.

Organized and directed classroom training of advanced JavaScript and jQuery programming as well as outlining best-practices for coding and web site development.

Web Developer

GSI Interactive, Inc - May 2008 to October 2009

Implemented designs from comps for several clients including: PBS, iRobot, Ace Hardware, Levi's Jeans, Toys 'R Us, Bath & Body Works, Modell's, Rockport Shoes, GNC. Projects included integration of JSP and JSTL scripting with standards-based CSS and XHTML. Emphasis on cross-browser compatibility and W3C standard's compliancy.

Integrated custom JavaScript API based on the Prototype JavaScript API. Extended event-based UI objects for both production and demonstration environments. Created tutorials and sample code for co-workers. Implemented several industry standard technologies including Prototype, jQuery, Suckerfish, and sifr.

Developer

Homenet, Inc - September 2006 to May 2008

Developed centrally managed business application to consolidate disparate web applications. Project included new application development, code upgrade, and integration with existing application code. System includes inventory listings, search functionality with AJAX integration, and visitor traffic reporting.

Developed integrated closed auction system for internal client use. Project included independent user/role system with editable permissions, proxy-bidding, and configuration interfaces for automation of client inventory transfer into auction system.

Developer responsible for upgrading and maintaining 1200+ individual inventory web applications. Daily tasks include customization of existing live applications and templates as well as development of new components to fulfill client requests.

Responsible for redesigning server and static web pages to eliminate "tag soup" and make full use of external CSS, dynamically-generated JavaScript, and reusable ASP function calls.

Analyzed and updated SQL Server database tables to adapt existing systems with changing requirements based on client requests.

Participated in code documentation review and flowcharting.

Coordinate with Graphics Department and Sales Department to estimate project scope

Responsible for error discovery, analysis, and correction for data system utilizing multiple data input sources and transfer mechanisms.

Developed new Data Analysis Reporting requirements.

Developed detailed description of routine job duties, procedures, and management checklists for the Quality Assurance Department.

Comptroller

Ferraro Cadillac, Inc - May 1993 to September 2006

Developed custom browser-based inventory management system, which replaced several data entry systems.

Reduced company Internet expenses by 83% through custom application development and thorough knowledge of current web hosting practices and values.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology

Capella University - Minneapolis, MN October 2005

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Creative

Experienced Adobe Photoshop designer.

Directed and edited DVD's for public distribution.

Technical

Active participant in StackOverflow.com.

Designed, coded, and launched web application for annual community variety show event.

Computer Technical Support - World Café Live.

Production Assistant - Studio Jams for BET Jazz TV Network.